Register of the Russia. Posol'stvo (U.S.) Records, 1897-1947.
Hoover Institution Archives
- Russian State Control Office File, 1917-1921.
  - Russian Supply Committee
    - Subagencies (Box 328)
      - Transportation Department
        - Audit
          - General
            - 1918-1919 (Folder 5)
              Available on microfilm reel 396
            - 1919
              - January (Folder 6)
              - January-February (Folder 7)
              - February (Folder 8)
          - Appendices (Box 331)
            - General
              - 1918 (Folder 1)
              - 1919 (Folder 2)
            - Statements of accounts (Folder 3)
              Available on microfilm reel 397
        - Merchant Marine Commission -- subagency
          - Audit (Folder 4)
          - Board sessions. Minutes
            - 1917-1918 (Folder 5)
            - 1918 (Folder 6)
  - "Svedeniia o deiatel'nosti Gosudarstvennogo kontrolia v SShA"--see Composition and structure/General/Reports
  - United States Shipping Board--see Commission on Russian Freighters Returned by the United States Shipping Board
  - "Zhurnal dlia zapisi bumag, postupaiushchikh na zakliushenie Gosudarstvennogo kontrolia"--see Composition and structure/General/Correspondence/1920
- Russian Supply Committee Office File, 1915-1918.
  Available on microfilm reels 397-445
  Administrative orders, clippings, correspondence, delivery registers, financial records, investigation reports, printed matter, receipts, reports, tables, arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Unidentified departments (Box 332)
    - Register of Correspondence
      - Incoming (Folder 1)
      - Outgoing (Folder 2)
    - Time book (Folder 3)
  - Agricultural Department (Folder 4)
  - All-Russian Zemstvos and Cities Union. American Commission
    - General
      - Letters (Folder 5)
      - Telegrams
        - Incoming (Folder 6)
        - Outgoing (Folder 7)
    - Commercial products
      - General (Folder 8)
        Available on microfilm reel 398
      - Military shoes
        - 1917
          - January-September (Folder 9)
          - October-November (Box 333, Folder 1)
        - 1918 (Folder 2)
    - Employees (Folder 3)
    - Finance
      - 1917 (Folder 4)
      - 1917-1918 (Folder 5)
      - 1918 (Folder 6)
  - Anglo-Russian Subcommittee (Box 334, Folder 1)
    Available on microfilm reel 399
  - Artillery Commission
    - General
      - Financial records
        - 1914-1917 (Folder 2)
        - 1917 (Folder 3)
      - Orders, Administrative
        - 1916-1917 (Folder 4)
        - 1917-1918 (Folder 5)
    - Commercial products (Box 335)
      - General
        - 1916-1917 (Folder 1)
          Available on microfilm reel 400
        - 1916-1918 (Folder 2-3)
        - 1918 (Folder 4)
      - Detonating fuses (Folder 5)
      - Files (Folder 6)
    - Employees
      - General
        - Correspondence
          - 1916
            - October-November (Folder 7)
            - November (Folder 8-10)
          - 1916-1917 (Box 336, Folder 1)
            Available on microfilm reel 401
          - 1917 (Folder 2)
          - 1918 (Folder 3)
        - Registers (Folder 4-6)
        - Registers (Box 337, Folder 1-2)
          Available on microfilm reel 402
      - Ozol's, Karl (Folder 3)
        Available on microfilm reel 403
      - Petrov, Nikolai (Folder 4)
      - Strutsinskii, Nikolai (Folder 5)
    - Technical Bureau (Folder 6)
  - Central Statistical Department on Orders. (see also Report and Statistics Department)
    - 1917-1918 (Folder 7)
    - 1918 (Folder 8)
  - Chancery
    - General
      - Correspondence
        - General
          - General, 1917
            - January-December (Folder 9)
            - May-November (Box 338, Folder 1)
          - Covering letters (Folder 2)
          - Registers
            - Incoming
              - 1916-1917 (Folder 3)
              - 1917
                - April-December (Folder 4)
                Available on microfilm reel 404
                - December (Folder 5)
                - 1917-1918 (Folder 6)
            - Outgoing (Box 339)
              - 1916-1917 (Folder 1)
              - 1917
                - April-September (Folder 2)
                - September-December (Folder 3)
                Available on microfilm reel 405
          - Secret, 1916
            - January-August (Folder 4)
            - September-December (Folder 5)
        - Commissariat Administration of Petrograd Military District (Box 340, Folder 1)
        - Russian Embassy, Washington
          - General
            - 1917
              - July-September (Folder 2)
              - October-December (Folder 3)
            - 1918 (Folder 4)
          - Secret
            - 1916 (Folder 5)
            - 1917 (Folder 6-10)
              Available on microfilm reel 406
        - Russian General Staff, Petrograd (Box 341)
          - Incoming
            - 1915-1916 (Folder 1)
            - 1916
              - January-August (Folder 2)
                Available on microfilm reel 407
              - September-December (Folder 3)
          - Outgoing
            - 1915 (Folder 4)
            - 1916
              - January-February (Folder 5)
              - March (Folder 6)
              - April-May (Folder 7)
              - May-June (Folder 8)
              - July (Folder 9)
                Available on microfilm reel 408
              - August (Folder 10)
              - September (Box 342, Folder 1)
              - October (Folder 2)
              - November (Folder 3)
              - December (Folder 4)
            - 1917
              - January (Folder 5)
              - February (Folder 6)
              - March (Folder 7)
              - April (Folder 8)
                Available on microfilm reel 409
              - May (Folder 9)
              - June (Folder 10)
              - July (Box 343, Folder 1)
              - August (Folder 2)
        - Russian Government Committee, London
          - Letters
            - 1916
              - January-August (Folder 3)
              - August-December (Folder 4)
            - 1917 (Folder 5)
              Available on microfilm reel 410
          - Telegrams
            - Incoming
              - 1915-1916 (Folder 6)
              - 1916-1917 (Folder 7)
            - Outgoing
              - 1915 (Folder 8)
              - 1916
                - January-August (Folder 9)
                - August-October (Folder 10)
                - November-December (Folder 11)
              - 1917
                - January-April (Folder 12)
                - April-June (Box 344, Folder 1)
                Available on microfilm reel 411
                - July-August (Folder 2)
        - Special Commission on State Defense, Petrograd (Folder 3)
      - Financial records
        - 1916
          - January (Folder 4)
          - June-December (Folder 5)
        - 1916-1917 (Folder 6-7)
        - 1917
          - January-December (Folder 8)
            Available on microfilm reel 412
          - August-October (Box 345, Folder 1)
    - Allies' military missions in the United States (Folder 2)
    - Allison, J. Wesley (Folder 3)
    - Andrievskii, Ivan--see Posrednik, Russian American Commercial, Industrial, and Information Company
    - American Metal Company--see Lessing, Adol'f
    - Baldwin Locomotives Works (Folder 4)
    - Baron Drizen, Freighter (Folder 5-6)
    - Benham-Boyesen Company (Folder 7)
    - Brazil, Purchases in (Folder 8)
    - Brazol', Boris
      - General
        - Registers of correspondence, 1917
          - Incoming (Folder 9)
          - Outgoing (Folder 10)
        - Telegrams (Folder 11)
      - Baron Drizen, Freighter--see Chancery/Baron Drizen
      - Canadian Car and Foundry Company (Box 346, Folder 1)
        Available on microfilm reel 413
      - Cox' affair
        - General (Folder 2-9)
        - Correspondence (Box 347, Folder 1)
          Available on microfilm reel 414
        - Investigation records (Folder 2-3)
        - Petitions (Folder 4)
      - Westinghouse Electric Company (Folder 5)
    - Building management (Folder 6)
    - Colorado Fuel and Iron Company (Folder 7)
    - Commercial products
      - General
        - Correspondence
          - 1916 (Folder 8)
          - 1917 (Folder 9)
        - Register (Folder 10)
      - Chlorine phosgene (Folder 11)
        Available on microfilm reel 415
      - Explosives (Folder 12)
      - Horseshoes and other cavalry equipment (Folder 13)
      - Medical supplies (Folder 14)
      - Minerals (Folder 15)
    - Composition and structure
      - n.d. (Folder 16)
      - 1915-1916 (Box 348, Folder 1)
      - 1917 (Folder 2)
    - Contracts (Folder 3)
      Available on microfilm reel 416
    - Du Pont de Nemours, E. I. and Company
      - Agreement, 7 December 1916 (Folder 4)
      - Letters (Folder 5)
      - Registers of telegrams (Folder 6)
    - Foreign credits to Russian governments
      - Great Britain (Folder 7)
      - United States
        - Register (Folder 8)
        - Telegrams (Box 349, Folder 1)
    - Frankov, Feodosii (Folder 2)
    - German intelligence service--see Baron Drizen, Freighter
    - Germonius, Eduard (Folder 3)
    - Great Britain -- supply agencies
      - 1915-1916 (Folder 4)
      - 1916 (Folder 5)
      - 1916-1917 (Folder 6)
    - Imposters. (see also Allison, J. Wesley) (Folder 7)
    - Kamenets-Podol'sk, Freighter (Folder 8)
    - Kidder, Peabody and Company (Folder 9)
    - Kork, Oskar (Folder 10)
    - Krasitskii, Count (Folder 11)
    - Lessing, Adol'f (Folder 12)
    - Machy, H. L.--see Allison, J. Wesley
    - Maru, Freighter (Folder 13)
    - Morgan, J. P. and Company (Folder 14)
    - Paikin, A. M. (Box 350, Folder 1)
      Available on microfilm reel 417
    - Pelestrious, A. W. (Folder 2)
    - Posrednik, Russian American Commercial, Industrial and Information Company
      - 1916 (Folder 3)
      - 1916-1917 (Folder 4)
    - Russian freighters requisitioned by the Russian Government (Folder 5)
    - Russian Government Committee, London
      - Rules and regulations (Folder 6)
      - Typewriters (Folder 7)
    - Russian Provisional Government (Folder 8)
    - Russian State Control (Folder 9)
    - Russian Supply Committee
      - Board sessions
        - 1915-1916 (Folder 10-11)
        - 1915-1917 (Folder 12)
        - 1917-1918 (Folder 13-14)
      - Budget, 1917 (Box 351)
        - Correspondence (Folder 1-2)
          Available on microfilm reel 418
        - Explanatory note (Folder 3-5)
        - Tables (Folder 6)
      - Composition and structure
        - General
          - 1915-1917 (Folder 7)
          - 1916 (Folder 8)
          - 1917
            - March-November (Folder 9)
            - June-December (Folder 10)
          - 1917-1918 (Folder 11)
          - 1918 (Folder 12)
        - Awards and decorations (Box 352, Folder 1)
          Available on microfilm reel 419
        - Salaries and allowances
          - 1915 (Folder 2)
          - 1916-1917 (Folder 3)
          - 1917-1918 (Box 353, Folder 1)
          - 1918 (Folder 2-3)
            Available on microfilm reel 420
          - 1918 (Box 354, Folder 1-2)
        - Office supply (Folder 3)
        - Subagencies (Box 355)
          - Agricultural Department
            - General (Folder 1)
            - Borodin, Nikolai (Folder 2)
          - Anglo-Russian Subcommittee (Folder 3)
          - Artillery Commission
            - General (Folder 4-5)
              Available on microfilm reels 420 and 421
            - Employees
              - General (Folder 6)
                Available on microfilm reel 421
              - Dismissals (Folder 7-9)
            - Technical Bureau. Reports (Box 356)
              - 1915
                - December 20 (Folder 1)
                - December 22 (Folder 2)
              - 1916 (Folder 3-4)
          - Composition for Supervision of Fulfillment of Orders
            - Board sessions (Folder 5)
              Available on microfilm reel 422
            - Commercial products (Folder 6)
          - Financial Department
            - Correspondence (Folder 7)
            - Orders, Administrative (Box 357, Folder 1)
            - Register (Folder 2)
            - Report (Folder 3)
          - Food Department (Folder 4)
          - Legal Department
            - Composition and structure (Folder 5)
            - Pool Engineering Company (Folder 6)
          - Machinery Department (Folder 7)
          - Military Agent
            - 1915 (Folder 8)
            - 1916-1917 (Folder 9)
            - 1917 (Folder 10)
          - Military Technical Department (Box 358)
            - 1916 (Folder 1)
              Available on microfilm reel 423
            - 1917 (Folder 2)
          - Mission of Ways of Communication
            - General (Folder 3)
            - Lomonosov, Iurii (Folder 4)
          - Naval Department
            - 1915-1916 (Folder 5)
            - 1918 (Folder 6)
          - Transportation Department. (see also Chancery/Brazol', Boris/Cox affair)
            - General (Folder 7)
            - Medzykhovskii, K. Iu. (Folder 8-9)
    - Russian Volunteer Fleet (Folder 10)
    - Russman (Folder 11)
    - Sapozhnikov, Major-General (Folder 12)
    - Scandinavia--see Transit traffic via Scandinavia
    - Schmuck, Peter (Folder 13)
    - Shlenker, Iosif (Folder 14)
    - Southern Pacific Lines (Box 359, Folder 1)
      Available on microfilm reel 424
    - Telephone and telegraph. Bills (Folder 2)
    - Transit traffic via Scandinavia (Folder 3)
    - Traritsa, Freighter--see Russman
    - Western Union Telegraph Company--see Telephone and telegraph. Bills
    - Westinghouse Electric and Manufacturing Company
      - Advisory opinion (Folder 4)
      - Meeting in Springfield, 1917 (Folder 5)
    - Yoakim, Benjamin F.--see Allison, J. Wesley
    - Zaliubovskii, Aleksandr, Lieutenant-General
      - "Osoboe mnenie General-Leitenanta Zaliubovskogo po voprosu o predlozhennom g. Winour' om 'Proekte soglasheniia mezhdu Britanskim i Russkim Pravi- tel'stvami' otnositel'no uchrezhdeniia pri Russkom Zagotovitel'nom Komitete v Amerike 'Anglo-Russkoi' podkomissii." Typed copy (Folder 6)
      - "Soobrazheniia General-Leitenanta Zaliubovskogo o poriadke pomeshcheniia zakazov i o perevozke gruzov iz Severnoi Amerike." Typed copy (Folder 7)
  - Commission for Supervision of Fulfillment of Orders
    - Board sessions (Folder 8)
    - Commercial products (Box 360)
      - Detonating fuses (Folder 1)
        Available on microfilm reel 425
      - Smokeless powder (Folder 2)
    - Naval Department, Orders placed by (Folder 3)
  - Commission for Compiling Report on the Activities of the Russian Supply Committee
    - General
      - Correspondence (Folder 4)
      - Graphs (Folder 5)
    - Commissariat Department (Folder 6)
  - Financial Department
    - General
      - Clippings (Folder 7)
      - Correspondence
        - 1917 (Folder 8)
        - 1917-1918 (Folder 9)
      - Financial records
        - General
          - 1917 (Folder 10)
          - 1917-1918 (Folder 11)
        - Bank statements
          - 1915 (Folder 12)
          - 1916
            - January-June (Folder 13)
            - July-December (Box 361, Folder 1)
              Available on microfilm reel 426
          - 1917
            - January-June (Folder 2)
            - July-December (Folder 3)
          - 1918 (Folder 4)
        - Checkbook (Folder 5)
    - Allied purchasing representatives -- meetings, 1917 (Folder 6)
    - American Bank Note Company (Box 362, Folder 1-2)
    - American Red Cross (Folder 3)
    - Bankers Trust Company (Folder 4)
    - Bashkirov, Vladimir (Folder 5)
    - Black Tom Island Explosion (Folder 6)
    - Central Supply Committee of United Provinces of Moscow District
      - Budget (Folder 7)
      - Commercial products (Folder 8)
    - Commercial products (Folder 9)
    - Consulates -- savings banks
      - General
        - 1917 (Folder 10)
        - 1917-1918 (Folder 11)
      - Montreal (Folder 12)
      - New York (Folder 13)
    - Division of Supplies, Establishment of the (Folder 14)
    - Fabian, K.--see Central Supply Committee of United Provinces of Moscow District
    - Financial Agent (Folder 15)
    - Gaston, William & Wigmore, Inc. (Folder 16)
      Available on microfilm reel 427
    - Great Britain--see Seizure of cargo by British Government
    - Guaranty Trust Company--see Morton Truck and Tractor Company
    - Gudkov, Valentin (Folder 17)
    - Hamilton & Hansel, Inc. (Folder 18)
    - Imperial Russian Government, Credits to (Folder 19)
    - Marine Transport Service Corporation (Folder 20)
    - Morton Truck and Tractor Company (Folder 21)
    - Moscow Machine Tool & Engine Company (Folder 22)
    - National City Bank of New York. (see also Bankers Trust Company) (Folder 23)
    - New York Central Railroad Company (Folder 24)
    - Novitskii, Vladimir (Folder 25)
    - Petrograd Zemstvos and Cities Regional Committee for Army Supply (Folder 26)
    - Pioneer Fireproof Storage Warehouse (Folder 27)
    - Poluboiarinov, A. D.?, "Otchet o deiatel'nosti finansovoi chasti Zagotovitel'nogo Komiteta do obrazovaniia Finansovogo otdela." Typed copy (Folder 28)
    - Remington Arms Union Metallic Cartridge Company (Box 363)
      - General (Folder 1)
      - Correspondence
        - 1917
          - January-March (Folder 2)
          - March-May (Folder 3)
          - June-October (Folder 4)
        - 1917-1918 (Folder 5)
      - Printed matter (Folder 6)
        Available on microfilm reel 428
    - Romanov, Nikolai--see Marine Transport Service Corporation
    - Russia -- counterrevolutionary movements--see American Red Cross
    - Russian banknotes (Folder 7)
    - Russian church in North America (Folder 8)
    - Russian lottery bonds--see American Bank Note Company
    - Russian missions and legations (Folder 9)
    - Russian savings banks--see Consulates -- savings banks
    - Russian State Control (Folder 10)
    - Russian Supply Committee
      - Board sessions
        - 1917-1918 (Folder 11)
        - 1918 (Folder 12)
      - Subagencies
        - All-Russian Zemstvos and Cities Union. American Commission -- commercial products
          - General (Folder 13)
          - Leather (Folder 14)
        - Anglo-Russian Subcommittee (Box 364, Folder 1)
        - Chancery
          - Diplomatic mail pouch (Folder 2)
          - Report and Statistics Division (Folder 3)
        - Commissariat Department (Folder 4)
        - Legal Department (Folder 5)
        - Military Agent (Folder 6)
        - Mission of Ways of Communication (Folder 7)
        - Naval Department (Folder 8-9)
        - Transportation Department (Folder 10-11)
    - Russian Volunteer Fleet (Folder 12)
      Available on microfilm reel 429
    - Seizure of cargo by British Government
      - General (Folder 13-14)
      - Dora (Folder 15)
      - Oconee (Folder 16)
      - Vologda (Folder 17)
    - Shumatov, L. A. (Folder 18)
    - "System of Accounts." Report (Folder 19)
    - Tennessee Copper Company (Folder 20)
    - Ter-Asaturov, Dmitrii. (see also Poluboiarinov, A. D.? "Otchet o deiatel'nosti finansovoi chasti Zagotovitel'nogo Komiteta do obrazovaniia Finansovogo otdela." Typed copy)
      - 1917 (Folder 21)
      - 1917-1918 (Folder 22)
    - Uget, Sergei
      - 1916-1918 (Folder 23)
      - 1917-1918 (Folder 24)
    - United States Realty and Improvement Company, New York (Folder 25)
  - Machinery Department (Box 365)
    - Contracts, 1917
      - March-June (Folder 1)
      - June-July (Folder 2)
    - Correspondence (Folder 3)
  - Military Agent
    - General
      - Correspondence
        - General
          - 1916 (Folder 4)
          - 1916-1917 (Folder 5)
            Available on microfilm reel 430
        - Covering letters and receipts (Box 366)
          - 1916-1917 (Folder 1)
          - 1917 (Folder 2)
        - Letters (Folder 3)
        - Registers
          - 1915-1916 (Folder 4)
          - 1916-1917 (Folder 5-6)
          - 1916-1919 (Folder 7)
        - Telegrams
          - Incoming
            - 1915
              - October (Folder 8)
              - October (Box 367, Folder 1-2)
                Available on microfilm reel 431
              - October-November (Folder 3)
              - November (Folder 4)
              - November-December (Folder 5)
            - 1915-1916
              - Russian General Staff, Petrograd (Folder 6)
              - Russian Government Committee, London (Folder 7)
            - 1916 (Box 368, Folder 1)
              Available on microfilm reel 432
            - 1916-1917 (Folder 2)
          - Outgoing
            - 1915
              - September-October (Folder 3)
              - October-November (Folder 4)
              - November (Folder 5)
            - 1915-1916
              - Russian General Staff, Petrograd (Folder 6)
              - Russian Government Committee, London (Folder 7)
            - 1916 (Folder 8)
      - Delivery book (Box 369, Folder 1)
      - Financial records (Folder 2)
        Available on microfilm reel 433
      - Lists of files (Folder 3)
    - American Russian Chamber of Commerce (Folder 4)
    - Budget (Folder 5)
    - Canadian Car and Foundry Company
      - 1915 (Folder 6)
      - 1916 (Folder 7)
    - Cipher keys (Folder 8)
    - Colt's Patent Fire Arms Co. (Folder 9)
    - Commercial products. (see also Russian Supply Committee/Composition and structure)
      - General
        - 1916
          - January-February (Folder 10)
          - February-March (Folder 11)
          - April-June (Folder 12)
          - June (Folder 13)
          - September-October (Box 370, Folder 1)
            Available on microfilm reel 434
          - October-December (Folder 2)
        - 1916-1917 (Folder 3)
      - Metals (Folder 4)
      - Rifles
        - 1915-1916 (Folder 5)
        - 1916 (Folder 6)
        - 1917? (Folder 7)
      - Typewriters (Folder 8)
        Available on microfilm reel 435
    - Credits to Russian governments (Folder 9)
    - Diplomatic mail pouch--see Russian Embassy, Washington
    - Iatsin, Ensign (Folder 10)
    - Lopatinskii, Colonel (Folder 11)
    - Nekrasov, Colonel (Folder 12)
    - Papuga, Vasilii (Box 371, Folder 1)
    - Russian Embassy, Washington (Folder 2)
    - Russian Military Agent, London (Folder 3)
    - Russian Supply Committee
      - General
        - 1916-1917 (Folder 4)
        - 1917-1918 (Folder 5)
        - 1918 (Folder 6)
      - Board sessions
        - 1916
          - January (Folder 7)
          - Janaury-June (Folder 8)
        - 1916-1917 (Folder 9)
          Available on microfilm reel 436
        - 1917 (Folder 10)
      - Composition and structure (Box 372)
        - 1915-1916 (Folder 1)
        - 1916 (Folder 2)
      - Subagencies
        - Agricultural Department (Folder 3)
        - Anglo-Russian Subcommittee (Folder 4)
        - Artillery Commission, 1916
          - January-December (Folder 5)
          - August-November (Folder 6)
        - Commercial Agent (Folder 7)
        - Military Technical Department
          - General (Folder 8)
          - Barbed wire, 1916
            - January-June (Folder 9)
            - July-December (Folder 10)
    - Sandy Hook Military Reservation, West Point--see Zaihovskii, Captain
    - Zaihovskii, Captain (Folder 11)
  - Military Technical Department (Box 373)
    - General (Folder 1)
      Available on microfilm reel 437
    - Correspondence
      - Russian General Staff, Petrograd
        - Incoming
          - 1915-1916 (Folder 2)
          - 1916 (Folder 3)
        - Outgoing
          - 1915 (Folder 4)
          - 1916
            - January-June (Folder 5)
            - August (Folder 6)
      - Russian Government Committee, London
        - Incoming (Folder 7)
        - Outgoing (Folder 8)
          Available on microfilm reel 438
      - Russian Government Committee, London and Russian General Staff, Petrograd
        - Incoming (Folder 9)
        - Outgoing (Folder 10)